# Ralph Dugue

(201) 503-4408, rdugue1@gmail.com, https://www.linkedin.com/in/rdugue, https://ralphdugue.com/

#### **TECHNICAL SUMMARY**

Software engineer with over 10 years of experience doing full-stack mobile and web development for small to medium, fast growing businesses. Passionate about creating clean and intuitive user interfaces, with a focus on accessibility for all users.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Kotlin, Java, JavaScript, Typescript, Python

Frameworks: Android, Ktor, Vuejs, Spring

Tools: Android Studio, AWS, GCP, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jira

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Mobile Engineer - ActiveCampaign, LLC, Remote — MAR 2021 - OCT 2022

- Improved the accessibility of the CRM mobile application, by updating the login screen to work more effectively with Android Voice Access.
- Grew Android user base by developing features to increase parity with the web application using MVI, and Clean Architecture.
- Eliminated bugs, reduced boilerplate code, and addressed long standing technical debt by updating the mobile CRM application to use Dagger Hilt for dependency injection.
- Lead on refactoring the data-layer of the mobile CRM application to follow Clean Architecture more closely using Retrofit for network calls and Room/SQLDelight for local caching.
- Managed production release of new versions of the Android application to new users using Gitlab, AWS and Firebase.

### Android Engineer - FanReach, LLC, Remote — APRIL 2018 - FEB 2021

- Lead on transitioning the Android code base to being Kotlin first, leading to quicker development and more modern Android architectural practices.
- Worked on a team to develop a platform to build and maintain several Android applications for professional sports organizations and venues.
- Developed video and audio media players to Allow users to watch live sporting events and highlights, using ExoPlayer Android library.
- Developed a chat client powered by AI, that is integrated in several apps using Kotlin and coroutines.
- Developed an events calendar that is integrated into several apps.

# Software Engineer - Self-Employed, Remote — MARCH 2017 - APRIL 2018

- Consulted with several clients on leveraging serverless architectures through AWS Lambda and API Gateway as application backends.
- Developed MVP Vuejs human resources application.

# Software Developer - Telco Equipment & Support Services, Remote — AUGUST 2013 - MARCH 2017

- Developed several proof-of-concept Android applications.
- Modified and developed modules for the Odoo enterprise management platform(Python framework).

• Developed web application to track employee leave time using Python for backend and jQuey front-end. Setup web hosting for application using GCP App Engine.

## **EDUCATION**

BS, Computer Science - Computer Criminology - Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Certified Developer - Associate - Amazon Web Services** 

**Software Product Management Specialization - Coursera** 

Full Stack Web Development - Free Code Camp